this one is the newest m1 max macbook
pro as you can see i haven't even opened
it yet and that is because on today's
video we are going to do the unboxing
the configurations and the
customizations for developers with a new
macbook and when we are done customizing
this thing we are going to compare it
with the current intel macbook pro that
i have and we are going to see if the m1
macbooks are faster than intel macbook
pros and by how much now this video is
not only for m1 macbook owners if you
have an intel macbook pro you can still
follow these guys because it will
completely apply to you as well and if
you have a windows machine and you want
to configure your development
environment like a pro then please click
the link below because there you are
going to find a one hour and a half
guide into how to configure your windows
development environment using the wsl or
windows subsystem for linux let's get
started with the unboxing then the setup
and then the comparison between intel
and m1 let's go let's do this thing
[Music]
wow
i'm
very impressed already i didn't realize
how different it would feel but with my
hands it feels so different than the
other macbooks it really feels like a
different computer like seriously it's
thicker and
it feels like a tool it doesn't feel
like a pretty laptop it feels like a
tool
okay so
we're gonna plugged in the wi-fi
and that's it let's get started with the
setup first i am going to remove all the
icons from the dock i don't like having
so many icons on my dock and by default
apple puts everything there so i remove
them all to install different
applications without having to download
them from different websites separately
we're going to use homebrew we're going
to go to brew.sh and we're going to copy
paste this command in our
terminal once that's done we're going to
press enter to install the xcode command
line tools and when the installation is
complete we're going to paste these two
lines of code that will be on the next
steps section then we're going to quit
our terminal and we're going to restart
it again if you can run the brew command
that means that the installation was
successful with homebrew apart from
being able to install things like
node.js and python we can also install
applications as well so here i'm going
to do brew install dash cask and i'm
going to install some browsers i'm going
to install visual studio code and i term
2.
once the installation is completed those
applications will be on my mac
if you ever want to know which
application you can install using
homebrew all you have to do is go to the
website and search for the name if you
find it on the website that means that
it can be installed here we have google
chrome and this is the command that we
have to do if we want to install it
without having to download it by
ourselves
to configure our terminal we're going to
open i term we're going to go to
preferences we're going to click on
appearance and we're going to change the
theme to minimal
then we're going to go to profiles
sessions we're going to enable the
status bar and we're going to configure
it here we can drag and drop the
elements that we want to see on top of
our terminal like for example battery
level cpu and memory then if we want to
we can change the colors
and as you can see that gives us a nice
status bar of our terminal if you want
to change the color styles of your
terminal all you have to do is go to
item2colorskins.com
here you can find a lot of color schemes
that you can use when you find the one
that you like you're going to click on
the name you're going to save that file
in your computer then you're going to go
to where you downloaded that file and
you are going to remove the txt from the
name
then you're going to open the file and
that will import the color scheme to
item then all you have to do is go to
preferences
profiles
colors and select the color scheme that
you just installed to customize our
terminal even more we are going to
install all my zsh we're going to go to
the website and we're going to copy
paste this command
here we are going to paste it in our
terminal and when we are done you will
see that the input of your terminal will
change then we're going to go to power
level 10k which allows us to customize
our terminal to make it look like this
then we're going to click on the
installation we're going to click on all
my zsh and we're going to copy that line
of code we're going to paste that in our
terminal and when we are done we are
going to open the configuration file of
our terminal in visual studio code we
are going to replace the default theme
of our console with the power level 10k
team we're going to save that file and
we're going to kill our terminal
when the application starts again you
are going to see the power level 10k
configuration wizard
this is going to ask you if you want to
install the fonts required to make your
console look good we're going to say yes
to this and that is going to download
and install the fonts for us after that
is finished we're going to kill the
console and when we open it again you're
going to see questions asking you to
confirm if you can see the icons
correctly if you can see all the icons
correctly you're going to answer yes to
all those questions and then you're
going to be able to configure your
prompt style there are many styles to
choose from and you can choose them
using the numbers in your keyboard you
can choose the shade you can choose the
time style you can choose the separator
you can choose the head you can choose
the tail there are many different styles
many different configurations so you can
choose whatever you want if at any point
in the process you feel like you made a
mistake and you want to start again all
you have to do is press the r
letter and that will restart the process
after you are done we are going to
choose verbose and we're going to choose
yes to apply the changes in our terminal
configuration file and we are done
now i'm going to run the command brew
install python 3 go prepamp mvm and gh
to install all those things as you can
see because they're not applications i
am not using the dash dash cask flag nvm
is the node version manager and gh is
the github cli application to complete
the nvm installation i am going to copy
these lines of code that are going to
show up at the end of that installation
command and i'm going to paste them in
the configuration file of my terminal
after i save that file then i am going
to kill my terminal again and i am going
to restart it one more time
there i will be able to run the nvm
command and now i am going to run the
mvm ls remote command this will allow me
to see all the different node.js
versions that are available for
installation this is very useful when
you need to run different programs in
different node.js versions because
sometimes things break i am going to
install the latest one for now by using
nvm install and the number that i want
and after that's done i'm going to
install the other one the latest lts
long-term support
version so i'm going to do mvm
install and the number one more time
now if i want to i will be able to
switch between those versions
as you can see my
console tells me the current node.js
version that i am at right now if i want
to switch to the default one i will do
nvm use default and if i want to go back
to the version 16 i'm going to do mvm
use and then the number that i want to
use as you can see nvm is pretty cool
now i'm going to run the gh command just
to check that the github cli works if it
works i am going to then run gh or login
here i'm going to login into github.com
using https and my browser the good
thing about the gh cli is the fact that
after you log in into it you will be
able to interact with github from your
command line and you don't have to go to
github.com anymore which is super super
cool
after we are done we are going to run
the code command that is going to open
visual studio code and here i am going
to install some of the extensions that i
need because i know i need many so i'm
going to skip that part but the ones
that i want to share with you are git
lens and the material icon theme they're
going to make your files look awesome
after this i'm going to search for the
community material team that i really
like we're going to select the shade of
the theme and when we are done we're
going to open our console to find out
that we don't have icons in the terminal
so to fix this all we have to do is go
to the settings of visual studio code
we're going to search for terminal font
and we're going to see where it says
integrated font family here we are going
to write the name of the font that we
installed in our terminal the name is
meslo lgs and f
when we save and we finish as you can
see our terminal now has the icons that
we want and that's it we are done and
our visuals to the code looks awesome
now this part is only for the m1 users
if you want to be able to work with m1
without problems you have to enable
rosetta which is sort of the translation
engine that apple has created so all you
have to do is run this command right
here and that is going to allow you to
run intel applications in your new m1
macbook pro after you do this you are
ready to go
now it's time to compare between m1 and
intel macbook pro the task they're going
to be performing is going to be building
a next js typescript application which
is the nomad coders website before we
see the results of the comparison
between m1 and intel i just want to say
that i feel like the comparison is not
going to be very fair to the intel
macbook pro and this is because the
intel macbook pro doesn't have as much
ram memory as my new m1 macbook pro so
this is why i feel like it's not a
one-to-one comparison because we have a
difference in ram memory okay so time
for the truth we're gonna run npm run
build in both of the computers and we're
going to see which one finishes first
and by how much difference the npm rom
build command is going to build the
nexus application is going to check the
typescript types and it's going to
generate the static pages let's see
[Music]
that is impressive that was a long time
that was a very big difference again i
don't know if it's because of the m1 or
more ram memory or whatever but still
this is crazy and this is a task that i
perform very very often so i'm super
happy that i'm going to get all that
time efficiency now that's amazing thank
you so much for watching this video
today i am very very impressed with the
new m1 macbook pro i am going to be
reviewing it later i think because i
have to basically work with it so far i
haven't done anything with it i just
installed what you saw me installed and
i haven't done anything else so i'm
going to work with it i'm going to start
running flutter and android and ios
simulators and react native and all
those things and i'm going to let you
know maybe later on a later video my
impressions and opinions about the
macbook pro m1
max so far that's it for this video
thank you so much for watching let me
know in the comments what do you think
what are your opinions do you want to
see a more configuration video do you
want to see the review what should i run
in this computer to check it out i don't
know about benchmarks you are better
than me at these things so thank you so
much for watching as always stay happy
stay free stay healthy eat kimchi
kamzamida salang hayo see you on the
next one bye